There was
a time when energy was a dirty word.
When turning on
your lights was a hard choice.
Cities in brownout.
Food shortages.
Cars burning fuel to run.
But that was the past.
Where are we now?
How do we make the world so much better?
Make deserts bloom?
Right now, we're the largest producer of
fusion energy in the world.
The energy of the sun trapped in rock,
harvested by machine
from the far side of the moon.
Today, we deliver enough
clean-burning helium-3
to supply the energy needs
of nearly 70% of the planet.
Who'd have thought?
All the energy we ever needed,
right above our heads.
The power of the moon.
The power of our future.
Rock and roll. 8:32 Pacific Time.
All Harvesters running smoothly.
Readouts are as follows.
Matthew, 14.6 miles.
Mark, 16.8 miles. I...
Hey, Gerty. Gerty. We gotta...
Good morning, Sam.
We got a live one on Mark.
I'm gonna go out now and rope her in.
Okay, Sam.
I want chocolate.
I think you're sweet enough.
You don't need chocolate.
Searching for long-range comms.
Signal failure on long-range comms.
Sam Bell reporting
to Central. 10:14 Pacific Time.
I've got a full container
of helium-3 ready to roll.
By the time this message reaches you,
it should be in transit.
Otherwise, everything running smoothly.
How are things down there?
You guys been to any
good parties or anything?
Oh, thanks for the football feed.
It almost felt live... Almost.
But three years is a long haul, you know.
It's way, way, way, way, way too long.
I'm talking to myself on a regular basis.
So...
Time to go home, you know what I mean?
That's it. Over and out.
Rock and roll. God bless America.
I can do that for you, Sam.
God damn it. I said I got it.
Why don't you listen to me?
Ready for launch.
Sam, is everything okay?
- Sam?
- What?
You don't seem like yourself today.
- Has something happened?
- You know...
Can you turn that off?
Please. Jesus Christ.
Sam, it might help you to talk about it.
Gerty, have you heard anything new
about anyone fixing Lunar Sat?
No, Sam.
What I understand is it's fairly low on
the company's priority list right now.
You tell them to sort that out, you
know what I'm talking about?
That's not...
I've only got two weeks,
but it's not fair
to whoever is coming up here next.
I will, Sam. Do you want me to finish
cutting your hair later?
No, come on, let's finish this.
Another one of those headaches.
Gerty, can you give me something for it?
Message received
from your wife, Sam, via Jupiter link.
Fuck.
Hi, Sam. It's me.
I got your last message.
It was really good to hear your voice.
I miss you, too.
I know you're really lonely up there,
but I think,
in a lot of ways,
it's been really good for you.
For both of us.
God, I hope you don't
mind me saying that.
I'm proud of you.
Someone's got something to say.
What did you want to say to Daddy, baby?
Say, astronaut.
Astronaut, Daddy.
Who's an astronaut? Daddy's an astronaut.
Say it really loudly.
Daddy's an astronaut.
Clever girl. Wave.
Give Daddy a wave.
Kathy, could you...
I can't believe you're
going to be home soon.
It's her birthday next month.
And I was thinking
about maybe a playhouse for the garden.
- Gerty.
- We could pick it out together.
Sam.
I love you.
And I miss you.
I miss you.
And I can't wait to see you.
Okay, sweetheart. Bye.
Hi, Doug.
You're really full of yourself,
aren't you, Doug?
Kathryn.
Not good.
What about Dumbo?
Doesn't he object to your...
Yes. Darrin objects.
But it's a special
occasion because of the morning light.
Ah, fuck! God damn it!
Fuck!
It's gotta smart, doesn't it, Gerty?
Sam, can I ask how it happened?
I told you, I saw something on TV and
I spilled boiling water on my hand.
You saw something on TV?
Yeah, I saw something
on TV that distracted me.
Is there something wrong with that, Gerty?
Sam, you said
it was the TV that distracted you.
But when I came in, the TV wasn't on.
Perhaps you were imagining things.
Yeah, you think too much, pal.
You need to get laid.
I'm going to go back to work.
I am the one and only
Oh, yeah!
Okay. Shut up.
Morning, Gerty.
Morning, Sam.
How are you today?
Fine. Fine.
- How's the hand?
- Oh, it's a little sore.
Little sore. It's okay.
What's for breakfast?
The usual.
Two weeks to go, Sam.
Two weeks to go, buddy.
Would you like
some hot sauce on your beans?
No, my tummy's a little tender, actually.
But thank you. Thank you, Gerty.
You're welcome, Sam.
8:19 Pacific Time.
Readouts are as follows.
Matthew, 9.8 miles.
Mark is nine...
Hey, Gerty...
Rock and roll.
Mark...
Mark's 11 miles on the button.
Luke's a little twitchy today.
Hey, Gerty,
looks like
we got a live one out on Matthew.
I'm gonna go out in a few minutes.
I'm just going to finish my coffee, okay?
Okay, Sam.
Searching for long-range comms.
Signal failure on long-range comms.
Danger. Atmospheric compromise.
Where am...
Where am I?
Sam, you're in the Infirmary.
You had an accident.
Do you remember what happened?
No, I don't...
I don't remember a thing.
Do you remember me?
Yeah, of course I remember you, Gerty.
That's good. That's very good.
It's nice to see you awake again.
I'd like to keep you
under observation here in the Infirmary
for a few days and run some tests.
How long have I been out?
Not long, Sam.
Go back to sleep.
Okay, bro.
You're still very tired.
We can talk later.
Hello?
...good working order, but we only have
two working Harvesters now.
Come on, come on.
Yeah, well, that's no surprise,
but it's not good enough.
Gerty, we're gonna
have to find a way to ramp up production
- on Mark and John.
- I know.
This is incredible. How do you manage
to fucking break a Harvester
and an employee, all in the same day?
These were extraordinary
circumstances, as you know.
Gerty, what's the status on Harvester 3?
How are the repairs going ahead?
- Sam. You're out of bed.
- Yeah.
I wanted to stretch my legs. Who was that?
We've been having
some problems with the Lunar Sat,
and our live feed seems to be down.
I was recording
a video message for Central,
updating them on your progress.
Sam, you need to stay in bed.
You're not ready to walk around yet.
All right.
Could you give me
my sunglasses? It's really bright in here.
Give me my...
Give me all my stuff, you know.
Your belongings are in your quarters, Sam.
- Well, bring it in here.
- Certainly.
Excellent, Sam.
What...
When can I get out of here, Gerty?
Sam, you may have
suffered from brain damage in the crash.
This would explain your slight memory loss
and logic impairment.
So, what's the diagnosis?
When can I get back to work?
Central has asked me to
slow down the Harvesters
to ensure you have time
to recuperate and get your strength back.
That's terrific. It's fantastic.
You can return to
the sleeping quarters tomorrow,
but it will still be a few more days
before you can resume
anything like a normal work schedule.
- Let's try another test.
- I don't want to try another test.
Please, Sam.
Hey, Gerty.
You know about this?
Matthew's got no velocity readout.
He's completely still.
He must have stalled.
Well, he's obviously stalled.
Don't you think we should tell Central?
Unlock the doors and I'll go fix it.
I'll pass on your message.
Message received
from Earth via Jupiter link.
Sam, we appreciate the offer,
but you concentrate on feeling better.
Hey, we don't want you to take
any unnecessary risks.
- You're too important to us.
- You're to stay put.
That is an order.
It's an order, Sam. From Lunar.
And what we're
going to do is send a rescue unit
to tend to the stalled Harvester
and get the base back on its feet.
What the fuck is...
What the fuck...
- I'm sorry, Sam.
- What?
Sam, I'm under strict orders
not to let you outside.
I don't appreciate that.
Being treated like a child.
I don't appreciate it.
Gerty!
Gerty! Gerty, come here!
What happened?
I don't know. Meteorites.
There have been no meteorites, Sam.
Micro-meteorites maybe, I don't know.
Either way, there might be
damage to the exterior shell.
I think you'd better... You'd better
let me go outside and take a look.
There is no damage to the exterior shell.
Well, it's not that
I don't believe you, Gerty,
but I mean, you know,
this thing is springing leaks
like an Acme fire hose.
You need to let me
go outside and fix this problem, Gerty.
I can't let you go outside, Sam.
Gerty, if you don't
let me go outside, we can't fix this leak.
I'm not permitted to let you go outside.
Just let... We'll keep it
between you and me. Okay, pal?
This thing
is springing gas, let's go. Come on.
Just to check the exterior shell.
- Yeah, of course.
- Okay, Sam.
Thank you.
Gerty.
Searching for long-range comms.
Signal failure on long-range comms.
Gerty! Gerty!
I found him outside.
By the stalled Harvester.
Who is he? Who is he?
We need to get him to the Infirmary.
You tell...
You tell me who that is.
You tell me who that is!
Sam Bell.
We need to get him
to the Infirmary immediately.
Hello, Sam.
How are you feeling?
Where... Where am I?
The Infirmary.
You had an accident out
by one of the Harvesters.
- Do you remember?
- I'm...
I'm thirsty.
I could get you some water.
I saw someone out there, Gerty.
I saw someone out there.
Sam, you suffered
a slight concussion in the crash
and have incurred minor injuries.
But all in all, the prognosis is good.
I'm happy to see you again.
- Gerty.
- Yes, Sam.
Is there someone in the room with us?
Sam, get some sleep.
You're very tired.
Spoke to Thompson today. Now that
you're up there, he's promising the world.
I think it was the right thing.
But...
It's just such a long time.
But I suppose there are things...
You know, that needed to happen.
I... I need time to think.
Listen, Sam...
be safe, and I'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
Gerty...
Gerty, what the... What...
What the hell's going on?
Who's the guy...
Who's the guy in the Rec Room?
Where did he come from?
Why does he look like me?
Sam, you're out of bed.
Yeah, Gerty, I'm out of bed.
Who's the guy...
Who's the guy in the Rec Room?
Sam Bell.
Come on, come on, come on.
You are Sam Bell.
Sam, what is it?
It might help to talk about it.
Gerty, I don't understand
what's happening.
I'm losing my mind.
We could run some tests.
I haven't let Sam contact Lunar.
They don't know you were recovered alive
from the accident...
Recovered alive?
What do you mean... What are you talk...
Why didn't you report it
to Central? What are you talking about?
I'm here to keep you safe, Sam.
Are you hungry?
Two weeks, two weeks, two weeks...
Two weeks, two weeks, two weeks, two
weeks, two weeks, two weeks...
Just getting my slippers.
- I'm using them. I'm using them.
- No. What?
These are mine.
Gerty says you're Sam Bell.
I'm Sam Bell, too.
What?
We've got that going for us.
Why...
How long have you...
What?
How long have you been here?
About a week.
So, how you doing?
- What?
- How are you doing?
How am I... How am I doing?
How do you think I'm doing?
Good job.
They locked all the exits.
Who's looking after the Harvesters?
Harvesters are fine.
It's affected them.
Here, talking to a clone,
that's slightly troubling.
I'm not a clone.
You're the clone.
Okay, Sam, you're not a clone.
Hey. Hey, Ridley,
you're not looking too good.
Butt out of this.
Davey, I'm talking
to Ridley. How you doing, pal?
Hey, I think Kathryn
likes you. I think she likes you, pal.
You're not looking too good, my friend.
Sorry you're not feeling too well.
You talking to yourself?
- I'll just get you all fixed up.
- How long have you been here?
Oh, I guess about three years.
Almost three years.
Listen, I...
I wanted to thank you.
I wanted to thank you for...
If it wasn't for you,
I guess I'd still be
in that crashed rover.
You saved my life and...
Hey, I know this is weird, you know.
I'm real lonely, you know...
I just want to shake your hand.
Will you shake my hand?
Maybe later.
What are you looking at?
You look just like me. It's incredible.
Why do I look like you?
Why don't you look like me?
We look like each other,
I guess. Hey, you know...
It's weird for me, too, you know.
Fuck.
Hey.
Hey, you wanna play some Ping-Pong?
No.
Come on, I'll teach you.
It'll help you relax.
- What's the score?
- 2-18.
Okay.
Do you want me
to show you how to hold that?
No. No, I...
I don't need you to
show me how to hold it.
- Okay. Okay.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Should we, uh... Should we play?
- Yeah.
God! Shit!
- 19-2.
- Yeah.
Do you want a stick of gum?
You know, we could
approach this in a different way.
Remember when we went to flight school...
What are you doing?
I'm fixing the net.
It's very Zen, Ping-Pong.
You have to just relax.
How long did it take you to do that?
Well, I don't remember doing all of it.
I remember
doing the church, and the Salvation Army,
and a few of the people.
My mind's been acting
kind of weird lately.
That's Fairfield, right?
There's the Town Hall.
Fairfield? Of course,
you know about Fairfield.
Yeah, there's Tess and Eve.
Do you know Tess?
Yeah. I know Tess.
- You know about Eve, right?
- What?
I had a... We had a girl.
Eve.
Isn't she beautiful?
She's my little monkey.
She's our little monkey.
High-five.
She might be the milkman's,
but she's beautiful.
Sam, a new message
has arrived from Earth.
Oh, shit.
- Greetings, Sam.
- How's our man?
You feeling better?
You have enough rest?
Okay, you resting up, Sam?
You better be, you bastard.
Well, enjoy it while
it lasts. We've got some good news.
The Jupiter Program
had to be put on hiatus,
so we got a few pairs of hands for you.
So, what we've managed to do is secure you
a Rescue Unit ahead of schedule.
Rescue Unit Eliza.
Now, Eliza has been stationed on
Goliath 19 for the last two months.
Now we expect them
to reach you in approximately 14 hours.
So commence to jump for joy.
You're about to be back in work.
In the meantime,
hang in there. Rest up.
You hang in there, Sam. Over and out.
They're sending a Rescue Unit?
Why? Why are they
sending a Rescue Unit?
To fix the stalled Harvester.
They didn't think I was up to it.
Well, then I'm going back.
That's it for me.
What?
Is that what you really think?
Yeah.
I've got a contract. I'm going home.
You're a fucking clone.
You don't have shit.
- Hey, I'm going home.
- You're not going anywhere.
You know, you've been
up here too long, man.
You've lost your marbles.
What, do you think Tess is back home,
waiting for you on the sofa in lingerie?
What about the original Sam? Huh?
I'm the original Sam!
I'm Sam fucking Bell!
- Hey, hey. Whoa.
- Me! Me!
Gerty, am I a clone?
Are you hungry?
Hey, hey.
Don't get your fucking panties in a twist.
I'm in the same boat, asshole.
- Listen. What about the other clones?
- What?
We might not be
the first two to be woken up.
You said that model had
already been started when you got here.
Well, who started it?
There might be others up here right now.
Think about it. How did I get up here
so quickly after your crash?
- I don't want to talk about it.
- They didn't ship me in from Central.
There wasn't time.
I must have come from the base.
I don't know what you're smoking.
Why would they do that?
That's ridiculous.
Impossible.
I bet there's some kind of secret room.
Secret room?
Yeah, a secret room.
Why not?
You're the one who's lost your marbles.
I've been here for three years, man.
I know every inch of this base.
I know how many... How much dirt's
between those wall panels over there.
Why would they do that?
What's the motive?
Look, it's a company, right?
They have investors.
They have shareholders.
Shit like that.
What's cheaper?
Spending time and money
training new personnel,
or you just have
a couple of spares here to do the job.
It's the far side of the moon.
The cheap fucks haven't even
fixed the communications satellite yet.
Tess would know.
She would have told me.
Hey, Geppetto, wake up.
You really think they
give a shit about us?
They're laughing all the way to the bank.
Tess would know.
She would have told me...
What do you get off
fucking sitting there,
sulking like a little fucking boy!
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- Wake up!
I bet there's some area
that we don't know about.
And I'm gonna find it.
Yeah, maybe
you'll find some buried treasure, too.
Fuck!
Eliza arrival estimated 13 hours.
You found your secret room?
Just put that anywhere.
Now, that's a good idea. That's...
That's where I keep my leprechauns.
- Get out of the way.
- What? Why?
I want to look underneath that model.
You're not touching this model.
Get the fuck out of the way.
Listen, why don't you relax, okay?
Why don't you
take a pill? Bake a cake?
- Go read the encyclopedia or something?
- You're a tough guy now?
What, are you going to stab me?
No, I'm a peaceful warrior.
I'm a lover. I'm not a fighter.
Put the knife down.
- Hey, hey, just...
- I want to look underneath there.
- Put the knife down.
- No. I'm not going to give you the knife.
- Just get out of the way.
- Take it easy 'cause I...
- Let go of the knife.
- Don't ever tell me what to do, okay?
Just... You let go. Let go of the knife.
- Don't be an asshole.
- Don't push me.
- Don't push me, motherfucker.
- Let go.
Let go.
Fucking told you
to let go of the goddamn knife.
Little fucking...
Fucking little girl, man!
- God damn it!
- No! No!
God damn it.
What did I tell you?
Okay, okay...
You gonna stop?
Okay, okay.
Jesus! Fuck...
Fuck me. What the fuck?
I hardly...
I hardly touched you.
- My fucking eye, man.
- Let me see.
- That's a lot of blood.
- Get off of me!
That's enough.
Well, appealing...
Nice feet, sexy...
Hello, Sam.
- Sam, is everything okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah, we had a fight,
me and the other guy, the other...
He's very angry, you know.
Know what he did?
He flipped my entire model over.
Know how much work I put into that thing?
Nine hundred and thirty-eight hours.
Nine hundred and
thirty-eight hours, yeah, exactly.
thirty-eight hours, really?
Approximately.
He's got a problem.
He scares me, Gerty.
What is it about Sam that scares you?
How he flies off the handle.
I see it now.
I see what Tess was talking about.
I never told you this, Gerty, but she...
She left me.
Tess left me, for six months.
She moved back in with her parents.
I know.
She gave me a second chance.
I promised her I'd change.
You have changed, Sam.
Hey, Gerty, since
I've been up here, I've sent Tess...
I've sent her over 100 video messages.
Where did those messages go?
Did they ever reach her?
Sam, I can only account
for what occurs on the base.
What about the messages she sent to me?
Sam, I can only account
for what occurs on the base.
Gerty...
Am I really a clone?
When you first arrived at Sarang,
there was a small crash.
You woke up in the Infirmary.
You suffered
minor brain damage and memory loss.
I kept you
under observation and ran some tests.
I remember, yeah. I remember that.
Sam, there was no crash.
You were being awakened.
It is standard procedure
for all new clones
to be given tests
to establish mental stability
and general physical health.
Genetic abnormalities
and minor duplication errors in the DNA
can have considerable impact on...
What about...
What about Tess? What about Eve?
They are memory implants, Sam.
Uploaded, edited memories
of the original Sam Bell.
I am very sorry.
Sam, it's been
several hours since your last meal.
Can I prepare you something?
Rescue arrival estimated 11 hours.
Okay, sweetheart?
Yeah, I'm staring into space. Get it?
- Funny.
- Hey...
Thanks for this. This is good.
This is cozy.
How's the... How's the nose?
Much better, thank you.
I went haywire before, you know, I...
I lost it and I'm...
- I'm sorry about that.
- It's okay.
No, it's not okay. I fucked up Fairfield.
I fucked up your model.
I don't know
what's wrong with me. I got a...
I got a temper.
I gotta do something about it.
Yes, you do.
Hey, can you turn that off for a second?
I want to talk to you.
Can you turn that off? Listen...
Listen, I wasn't supposed to... I'm...
I'm trying to tell you something.
Can you turn...
Lunar instructed Gerty to...
Listen to me.
I wasn't supposed to find you...
- Tough guy.
- Listen to me...
- You look like a...
- What?
- ...radioactive tampon.
- I wasn't supposed to...
Or like a banana with a yeast infection.
Listen to me.
I wasn't supposed to find you.
Lunar instructed Gerty to lock me inside
the base while you were out there.
And there's something else.
Right around the time I was awakened,
I walked in on Gerty talking to Central.
He was having a live conversation.
- A live conversation?
- Yeah.
How do you know
it was a live conversation?
Because it was a back and forth exchange.
Communications equipment
was damaged. There was a solar storm.
It was live, man. It was live.
That's impossible.
There was a flare. It fried the satellite.
The satellite's fine. They don't
want us to be able to contact Earth.
They lied to us.
They've been lying to us
since the beginning.
They... They've been
lying to us since forever.
If the satellite works,
how are they blocking
the live feed from down here?
Everything works fine.
Maybe they're not
blocking the signal from inside the base.
From where then?
Searching for long-range comms.
I'm just passing the
last of the Harvesters. Looks like John.
Searching for long-range comms.
How long until you're out
of the base's range?
About a minute.
Ninety seconds, tops.
- You ever been out this far?
- No.
- Signal failure on long-range comms.
- Never have.
Leaving Sarang working perimeter.
You see anything?
It would help if
I knew what the hell I was looking for.
Wait a second, I see something.
Approaching Station 3.
Holy shit.
I think I see something, too.
Approaching Station 1.
You see what I see?
Looks like an antenna
or a pylon or something.
I think it's the jammer.
I knew it.
This is why we're not
getting the live feed.
Sam? Can you hear me?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I hear you.
Yeah.
Listen, I'm not feeling too good.
I'm gonna head back to the base.
Okay, I'm gonna
stay out here for a little while.
I'm gonna see if
there's any more of these things.
Fuck, fuck.
Fuck, fuck. Fuck.
Access denied.
Password accepted.
Accessing Sam Bell database.
I'm done.
Fifteen point...
My hair's falling out.
I'd better start for home...
For the last time, over and out.
The pod is designed to
put you into a deep sleep
for the duration of your
three-day return journey back to Earth.
Safe trip.
Fuck.
Here she is.
I'm gonna go and see her soon.
Lunar Industries remains
the number one provider
of clean energy worldwide
due to the hard work of people like you.
Rescue arrival estimated nine hours.
Lay down, relax, and breathe deeply.
The cryogenic protection pod
is designed to put you into a deep sleep
for the duration of your
three-day return journey back to Earth.
As you begin to feel sleepy,
think about
the magnificent job that you've done
and how proud your family are
of what you've accomplished.
Lunar Industries remains
the number one provider
of clean energy worldwide
due to the hard work of people like you.
Safe trip,
Annyeonghi gaseyo, and goodbye.
Approaching Station 2.
Hey, I saw three more of those jammers.
I think the base is surrounded.
I printed out the coordinates.
What's wrong with you?
What's going on?
I found your secret room.
Who goes first?
I go first.
Jesus Christ, there's so many of them.
Why are there so many of them?
Sam, can I help you with something?
Not now, Gerty. I'm okay.
Gerty...
Why did you help me before?
With the password?
Doesn't that go against
your programming or something?
Helping you is what I do.
Leaving Sarang working perimeter.
Searching for long-range comms.
Signal re-established.
Hello?
Is this the Bell residence?
This is the Bell residence.
Could you call back?
There's something wrong with the picture.
I'm trying to reach Tess Bell.
I'm sorry.
She passed away some years ago.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I think so. I'm her daughter.
Can I help you?
Eve?
- Yeah?
- Hi. Hi, Eve.
How old... How old are you now?
I'm 15.
- Do I know you?
- Oh, sweetheart.
How did Mommy die, sweetheart?
How did Mommy die?
Dad?
Yeah?
There's someone asking about Mom.
Who's asking about Mom?
That's enough. That's enough.
I want to go home.
Eliza arrival estimated in seven hours.
Ow, fuck. Shit.
- What, did you cut yourself?
- Yeah.
What are you laughing at?
Well, you don't hold it
like you're trying to stab somebody.
For God sakes.
Here, give me that.
You gotta hold it
closer to the blade, you see?
- Watch what I'm doing.
- Why are you shaking?
You carve out, like that.
That's it.
It's freezing in here.
Well, you're...
You're sitting under the fridge.
What's going on with you?
Are you all right?
Yeah, that crew they're sending in,
if they...
If they find us awake
at the same time, you know...
They're not gonna let us live.
You know that, right?
You know, their return vehicle is...
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Are you okay?
Maybe you should lay down for a while,
take some tranquilizers or something.
If I take some tranquilizers,
I'll never wake up again.
You'll be okay.
Everything's gonna be okay.
I'm freezing.
Hey, hey...
Hey.
I'm really scared.
Where are you going?
Hello?
Is this the Bell residence?
This is the Bell residence.
Could you call back?
There's something wrong with the picture.
I'm trying to reach Tess Bell.
I'm sorry,
she passed away some years ago.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I think so. I'm her daughter.
Can I help you?
Gerty, I need to talk to you.
Of course, Sam. How can I help?
We've found the hidden room.
We know about the others.
That hidden room, Gerty.
The lower deck
is out of bounds to awakened clones, Sam.
Gerty, we need to wake up a new clone.
New clones can only be awakened
once a three-year contract is completed.
Gerty, if we don't wake up a new clone,
me and the other Sam
will die, we will be killed.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Do you want me
and the other Sam to be killed?
That is the last thing I want.
Well, then you have to
wake up a new clone.
Okay, pal?
Eliza arrival estimated in five hours.
I am the one and only
God.
Hey.
What's going on? You okay?
Don't... Don't touch him.
Come here.
He's not conscious yet.
Gerty and I just woke him up.
Why? What's going on?
Come on. Come on outside.
When the rescue unit arrives,
they're gonna expect
to find a body in that crashed rover.
That guy?
What, are you going to kill him?
- Jesus Christ.
- What are you doing?
Zip up your fly.
You're burning up.
You sweat like a pig.
Put your hat on.
- Put your hat on.
- I'm hot.
Hey, if we go through with this,
I'm gonna need your help
hauling him out to the crash site.
What about us?
Eliza arrives, finds you
and me as a welcome party...
They're not going
to find you and me as a welcome party.
They're gonna find me,
and you're going back to Earth
before they get here.
In that helium-3 launcher.
I did the math.
You're gonna pull some Gs,
but it should...
It should be fine. You'll be all right.
You're going home.
You did your three years.
I can't expect you to stick around.
Maybe you can meet Eve in person.
I saw that VP. She's beautiful.
She's gorgeous. We did good.
High-five.
Go for it.
You go for it.
- You comfy?
- No.
- What?
- No!
What if I have to take a shit?
Just...
You'll have to hold it in, pal.
For three days?
That's the way it goes. Need a hand?
No.
Fuck off.
All right. No reason for hostility.
I'm just trying to help out.
Eliza arrival estimated three hours.
Hey. We need to do this.
We wait too long and
he's gonna be conscious.
Fuck me.
What's going on with you?
I changed my mind.
I'm not going back.
I don't think I can move my legs.
Besides, look at me...
I meet Eve now,
I'd scare the crap out of her.
What are you talking about, man?
She's your daughter.
She doesn't care what you look like.
You're not going to kill anybody.
We can't kill anybody.
You can't.
I know you can't, 'cause I can't.
You go.
You're a good guy, Sam.
It was a good plan, you know.
You just picked the wrong guy to go back.
You... You sure about this?
Yeah. You should travel, you know.
I always wanted to do that.
Amsterdam, or...
Yeah, you know, I was
thinking about Hawaii or maybe Mexico.
Aloha.
Bring me back
a piña colada, all right, bro?
Hey...
Johnny Spaceman.
You remember Tess came
in for that interview?
She was so beautiful.
She wasn't
the best candidate, but it didn't matter.
I had to give her the job.
I wanted to keep her in the country.
- She was going back to Ireland.
You knew you had to take a chance,
so you called her.
You were terrified. You wrote that whole
speech for her answering machine.
But you didn't need it,
'cause she picked up the phone.
She was, like, "Why is he calling me?"
"The internship's over.
Why's he calling me at home?"
I asked her if she wanted to go get like an
ice cream cone or something dorky like that.
She said, "Let's get a drink."
I said, "Okay. What do you..."
Sam, this is not going to work.
What? Why?
I've recorded everything
that has taken place since your awakening.
If anyone were to check my memory cache,
it would put you in considerable danger.
You could erase my memory banks.
I could reboot myself
once you have departed.
Are you okay with that?
I'm here to
keep you safe, Sam. I want to help you.
Eliza arrival estimated 24 minutes.
Sam.
Hey.
I set your...
I set your computer to reboot
the moment that I've launched.
I understand, Sam.
Then you should be okay.
I hope life on Earth
is everything you remember it to be.
Thanks, Gerty.
You gonna be okay?
Of course.
The new Sam and I will be
back to our programming
as soon as I've finished rebooting.
Gerty, we're not programmed.
We're people. Understand?
Eliza arrival estimated eight minutes.
Fuck!
Air lock pressurization complete.
Sam?
Hey, Sam?
You okay, buddy? Cavalry's here.
Where am I?
You're in the Infirmary.
You had an accident.
How long have I been out?
Not long, Sam.
Do you remember what happened?
...made contact. Yeah.
Yeah, Eliza?
He ain't going nowhere.
Bag him up and we'll
get started on repairs to the Harvester.
Dwight, I'm gonna need the...
Lunar Industries stocks
have slipped a further 32%
after accusations...
Clone 6, the clone of Sam Bell,
has been giving evidence at CAA's
Board of Directors meeting in Seattle...
You know what? He's one of two things.
He's a wacko or an illegal immigrant.
Either way, they need to lock him up.
Line two.